princeton.edu 2019-12-09

# Princeton University Privacy Notice | Princeton University

## Overview

This Privacy Notice applies to all Princeton University (the “University” or “we”) owned websites and apps, unless a different notice is provided.

The University reserves the right to modify this Privacy Notice at any time.   

## Links to Other Sites

Some University websites may contain links to external websites not owned or controlled by the University. The University is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

## Collection of Personal Information

Personal information is any information that personally identifies you or from which you could be identified. This may include information related to you that can be identified, directly or indirectly, by reference to an identifier such as an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to your physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural, or social identity.

The University collects personal information from you from a variety or sources, including from you directly (e.g. when you contact us, sign up for an account, complete a form online) and information we generate about you in the course of our relationship with you (e.g. information collected from cookies). By using the website, you consent to the collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Notice.

## Site Analytics

The University collects data about how users interact with websites and applications. This information is collected by third-party analytics providers on behalf of the University, and is used to evaluate and improve our websites and communication initiatives. 

## Cookies & Beacons

The University’s websites make use of persistent cookies to save preferences and temporary (session) cookies to track logins and allow for site analytics. Note that logged in users are individually identifiable to the web server through these cookies.

You can prevent the setting of cookies or selectively accept cookies by adjusting the preferences in your browser (please refer to your browser’s help function to learn more about cookie controls). If you turn off cookies, you may not be able to log in, and some web pages may not display properly.

A beacon is code that tracks how users interact with our websites. We use this information to improve our websites and online services, tailor our websites and online services to your likely interests, and conduct market research.

You may be able to turn off scripting functionality, such as JavaScript, within your browser (please refer to your browser’s help function). If you turn off JavaScript, there may be some features of our websites that will not be available to you, and some web pages may not display properly.

## Use of Log Data

University websites may collect personal information such as account names, netIDs, Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses, browser characteristics and times and dates of connections.

We may use log data to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our websites, analyze trends and track users’ use of websites to improve our websites, and to deliver customized and/or personalized content.

If you share personal information, including photographs, on any University website, social network, blog, or other such forum, please be aware that any information you submit can be read, viewed, collected, or used by other users, and could be used to contact you, send you unsolicited messages, or for purposes over which neither you nor the University have control. The University is not responsible for the personal information you choose to provide in these forums.

## University Use of Information

Your personal information will be used for administrative, educational and/or research purposes and in furtherance of the University’s mission. The use of your personal information is necessary for the legitimate interest of the University in carrying out its educational and research mission and performing University business, for complying with legal obligations, for protecting your or someone else’s vital interests, and/or for the public interest. 

## Third Party Use of Information

We do not sell the information we gather from individual visitors to our websites.

We may disclose your information to third parties as follows:

  * **Consent:** We may disclose your information to third parties if we have your consent to do so.
  * **Service Providers:** We may share your information with third parties that help us provide services and/or products to you, support our operations or to help fulfill the University’s obligations. 
  * **Required by Law:** We may share your information with third parties to the extent we are required to do so by law, court order, subpoena or other legal processes.
  * **De-Identified and Aggregate Information:** We may use and disclose your information in anonymized or aggregate form without limitation.

## Security, Retention and Disposition of Your Information

The University implements appropriate technical, physical and organizational security measures designed to protect the personal information we process that ensure a level of security appropriate to the risks presented by the processing and the nature of the data to be protected. While we strive to protect your information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of such information.

Your information will be retained or disposed of by the University in accordance with its records management principles and policies.

## Information for Data Subjects in the European Union

Subject to certain limitations and conditions, you have certain rights regarding the processing of your personal information, including the right to request access, correct, delete, restrict or object to our processing of, or receive a portable copy of, your personal information. You may exercise these rights by contacting [GDPR@princeton.edu](mailto:GDPR@princeton.edu). You may also have a right to lodge a complaint with your local data protection or privacy regulator. 

Your personal information may be transferred to, stored and processed in, a country that is not regarded as providing the same level of protection for personal information as the laws of your home country. We have put in place appropriate safeguards (such as contractual commitments) in accordance with applicable legal requirements to provide adequate protections for your personal information. For more information about the safeguards which the University has in place in connection with this transfer, please contact [infosec@princeton.edu](mailto:infosec@princeton.edu).

## Updates to This Policy

We may update or change this policy at any time. Your continued use of this site after any such change indicates your acceptance of such changes.

Last updated 10/29/18.
